Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco Papers
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Music, 1905-1968 (Box 1-106)
  - Arrangements, before 1940-1967
    - Anonymous
      - Three Sephardic songs (voice, piano or harp)
        - Voice part (Box-folder 100/9)
      - Three Sephardic songs (voice, orchestra)
        - Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 100/9)
      - Vos toig mir (voice, piano)
        - Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 100/11)
        - Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 100/11)
    - Bach, J. S.
      - The art of the fugue. Contrapunctus IV (instrumental ensemble)
        - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 102/1)
      - Partita in B minor (string orchestra)
        - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 100/12)
        - Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 100/12)
      - Suite no. 6 (string orchestra)
        - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 100/14)
        - Parts (Box-folder 100/14)
    - Bizet, Georges
      - L'Arlesienne. Minuet (2 pianos)
        - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 100/15)
    - Brahms, Johannes
      - 3 intermezzos (violin, piano)
        - Holograph manuscript score, see ML 96.C34 no. 92
        - Violin part, see ML 96.C34 no. 92
        - Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 100/16)
        - Violin part (Box-folder 100/16)
        - Printed score (Box-folder 100/16)
    - Chopin, Frédéric
      - Fantasie impromptu (violin, piano)
        - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 100/17)
      - Sixteen preludes (violin, piano)
        - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 102/2)
    - Dall' Abaco, Evaristo
      - Sonata, op. 4/12 (violin, keyboard instrument)
        - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 100/18)
        - Violin part (Box-folder 100/18)
    - Debussy, Claude
      - Minstrels (guitar)
        - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 100/19)
        - Printed score (Box-folder 100/19)
    - Khatchaturian, A.
      - Masquerade suite. Valse (2 pianos)
        - Printed score (Box-folder 101/1)
    - Mozart, W. A.
      - Don Giovanni. Serenade (violin, piano)
        - Holograph manuscript score, see also ML96.C34 no. 85 (Box-folder 101/2)
        - Violin part (Box-folder 101/2)
      - Don Giovanni. Serenade (violoncello, piano)
        - Holograph manuscript score, see ML96.C34 no. 87
      - The marriage of Figaro. Susanna (violin, piano)
        - 2 holograph manuscript scores (Box-folder 101/3)
        - Violin part (Box-folder 101/3)
      - The marriage of Figaro. Voi che sapete and Non so piu (violin, piano)
        - Holograph manuscript score, Caption title: Cherubino: two arias; see ML96.C34 no. 86
    - Pizzetti, Ildebrando
      - Four piano transcriptions from La pisanella
        - Holograph manuscript score, see ML96.C34 no. 82
    - Prokofiev, Sergei
      - Cinderella. Valse (2 pianos)
        - Printed score (Box-folder 101/4)
    - Ravel, Maurice
      - Jeux d'eau (violin, piano)
        - Holograph manuscript score, see ML96.C34 no. 93
        - Violin part, see ML96.C34 no. 93
        - Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 101/5)
        - Violin part (Box-folder 101/5)
        - Printed score (Box-folder 101/5)
      - Pavane pour une infante défunte (guitar)
        - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 101/6)
        - 2 manuscript scores (Box-folder 101/6)
        - Printed score (Box-folder 101/6)
      - Pavane pour une infante défunte (2 pianos)
        - Printed score (Box-folder 101/7)
      - Miroirs. Alborada del gracioso (violoncello, piano)
        - Holograph manuscript score, see ML96.C34 no. 88
        - Violoncello part, see ML96.C34 no. 88
      - Miroirs. La vallée des cloches (orchestra)
        - Holograph manuscript full score, see ML96.C34 no. 79
        - Photocopied holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 102/3)
        - Printed score (Box-folder 101/8)
        - Parts (Box-folder 101/8)
      - Miroirs. La vallée des cloches (violoncello, piano)
        - Holograph manuscript score, see ML96.C34 no. 89
        - Violoncello part, see ML96.C34 no. 89
    - Rossini, Gioacchino
      - The barber of Seville. Figaro (violin, piano)
        - Holograph manuscript score, see ML96.C34 no. 91
        - Violin part, see ML96.C34 no. 91
        - Violin part (Box-folder 101/9)
        - Printed score (Box-folder 101/10)
        - Violin part (Box-folder 101/10)
      - The barber of Seville. Figaro (violincello, piano)
        - Holograph manuscript score, see Ml96.C34 no. 95
        - Violoncello part, see Ml96.C34 no. 95
      - The barber of Seville. Figaro (violin, orchestra)
        - Holograph manuscript full score, see ML96.C34 no. 96
        - Photocopied holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 102/4)
      - The barber of Seville. Rosina (violin, piano)
        - Holograph manuscript score, see ML96.C34 no. 90
        - Violin part, see ML96.C34 no. 90
        - Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 102/5)
        - Violin part (Box-folder 102/5)
    - Schumann, Robert
      - Herberge (orchestra)
        - Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 101/11)
      - Nachtstück (chamber orchestra)
        - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 101/12)
    - Strauber, Rudolf
      - Sonata no. 1 (guitar, harpsichord)
        - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 101/13)
    - Tchaikovsky, Peter I.
      - Serenade for strings, op. 48. Valse (piano, 4 hands)
        - Printed score (Box-folder 101/14)
      - Serenade for strings, op. 48. Valse (2 pianos)
        - Printed score (Box-folder 101/15)
    - Verdi, Giuseppe
      - La traviata. Violetta (violin, piano)
        - Holograph manuscript score, see ML96.C34 no. 84
        - Printed score (Box-folder 101/16)
  - Music by other composers, 1935-1965
    - Cortese, Luigi
      - Sonata (horn, piano), Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 103/1)
    - Couture, Maurizio
      - Adagio (piano), Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 103/2)
      - Allegro ma non troppo (piano), Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 103/3)
      - Ballata (piano), Printed score (Box-folder 103/4)
      - Cinque appunti (piano), Printed score (Box-folder 103/5)
      - Dialogo romantico (piano), Printed score (Box-folder 103/6)
      - Minuetto (piano), Printed score (Box-folder 103/7)
      - Preludio (organ), Printed score (Box-folder 103/8)
    - Enos, Joseph
      - Sonnets nos. 30 and 71 (voice, piano), Photocopied manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 103/9)
    - Escovado, Robin
      - Ballade for Christmas (piano; 1956), Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 103/10)
      - Ballade for Christmas (piano; 1957), Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 103/11)
      - Ballade for Christmas (piano; 1959), Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 103/12)
      - Elegie (string orchestra), Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 103/13)
      - Jubilate deo (women's voices), Photocopied holograph manuscript vocal rehearsal score (Box-folder 103/14)
      - Lo di che han detto ai dolci amici addio... (piano), Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 103/15)
      - The night of the fox (piano), Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 103/16)
      - Overlooking the Hudson (piano), Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 103/17)
      - Ritorno ai Cipressi (piano), Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 103/18)
      - Time, like a golden butterfly (voice, piano), Photocopied holograph manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 103/19)
    - Galla-Rini, Anthony
      - Accordion chart, Printed / manuscript charts and musical fragments; Laid in: "A discussion on the multiple switch accordions"; typescript with attached program; [9] p. (Box-folder 103/20)
      - Concerto for accordion (accordion, piano), Printed score (Box-folder 103/21)
    - Gluck, C. W.
      - Orfeo ed Euridice. Spiagge amante (voice, piano), Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 103/22)
    - Hartmann, Klaus Amadeus
      - Gessangsszene (voice, orchestra), Printed full score (Box-folder 103/23)
    - Leonard, Joseph
      - Festival hymn (cantor, chorus, organ), Photocopied manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 104/1)
      - Festival prelude (organ), Manuscript score (Box-folder 104/2)
      - In memoriam (voices), Photocopied manuscript vocal score (Box-folder 104/3)
      - Ma tovu (cantor, organ), Photocopied manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 104/4)
      - Ode to youth (voices), Photocopied manuscript vocal score (Box-folder 104/5)
      - Prelude for Rosh Hashonoh (organ), Photocopied manuscript score (Box-folder 104/6)
      - Processional (organ), Photocopied manuscript score (Box-folder 104/7)
      - Romanza (string quartet), Photocopied manuscript score (Box-folder 104/8)
      - Romanza (organ), Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 104/9)
      - The Sabbath day (voices), Photocopied manuscript vocal score (Box-folder 104/10)
      - Silent devotion (organ), Photocopied manuscript score (Box-folder 104/11)
      - Un'sane tokef (voices), Photocopied manuscript vocal score (Box-folder 104/12)
      - With love everlasting (cantor, organ), Photocopied manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 104/13)
      - Zaddik-Kattomor (voices), Photocopied manuscript vocal score (Box-folder 104/14)
    - Lewandowsky, Louis
      - Vshomru (cantor, organ), Photocopied manuscript piano-vocal score; Arranged by Joseph Leonard (Box-folder 104/15)
    - Liuzzi, Fernando
      - Lamento della Madonna (voice, piano), Photocopied manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 104/16)
      - L’apparizione in Emmaus (cantor, chorus, piano), Photocopied manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 104/17)
      - Le vergini savie e le vergini folli (cantor, chorus, organ), Photocopied manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 104/18)
    - Lubin, Ernst
      - By the bay (voice, piano), Photocopied holograph manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 104/19)
      - The carnal and the crane (voices, piano), Photocopied holograph manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 104/20)
      - I shall know why (voice, piano), Photocopied holograph manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 104/21)
      - Le menuet de Roxane (flute, harp), Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 104/22)
      - Meditation and May the words (voice, organ), Photocopied holograph manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 104/23)
      - Chorale prelude on Vater unser (organ), Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 104/24)
      - Partita (brass quintet), Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 104/25)
      - Portrait (piano), Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 104/26)
      - String quartet, Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 104/27)
      - String quartet no. 2, Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 104/28)
      - Sonata (trombone, piano), Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 104/29)
    - Paskowitz, Adrian
      - Awake Deborah (chorus), Photocopied manuscript vocal score (Box-folder 105/1)
      - Jerusalem, stone on the hill (chorus), Photocopied manuscript vocal score (Box-folder 105/2)
      - Variations on two Israeli songs (viola, piano), Viola part (Box-folder 105/4)
    - Poddany, Eugene
      - Lento ma non troppo (piano), Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 105/5)
    - Previn, Andre
      - Overture to a comedy, Printed full score (Box-folder 105/6)
      - Three songs (voice, piano), Photocopied manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 105/7)
    - Pujadas, Mariblanca de
      - The music (voice, piano), Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 105/8)
    - Reed, H. Owen
      - The passing of John Blackfeather (voice, piano), Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 105/9)
    - Rietti, Vittori
      - Trionfo di Bacco e Arrianna (voices, piano), Photocopied holograph manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 105/10)
    - Rota, Nino
      - Sinfonia, Printed full score (Box-folder 105/11)
    - Rozsa, Miklós
      - Concerto (violin, orchestra), Printed full score (Box-folder 105/12)
      - Lullaby (women's chorus), Printed vocal rehearsal score (Box-folder 105/13)
      - Sonata (2 violins), Printed score (Box-folder 105/14)
    - Sangiorgi, Alfredo
      - Alla nonna (voice, piano), Photocopied manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 106/1)
      - Ave Maria (voice, piano), Photocopied manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 106/2)
      - Pianto antico (voice, piano), Photocopied holograph manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 106/3)
    - Sanford, Lee
      - Bassa-go-go (voice, unspecified instruments), Photocopied manuscript lead sheet (Box-folder 106/4)
    - Selden-Goth, G.
      - Praeludium und Fuge (2 pianos), Printed score (Box-folder 106/5)
    - Stein, Herman
      - Acting silly, Photocopied manuscript short score; Film sketch (Box-folder 106/6)
      - Main title, Photocopied manuscript short score; Film sketch (Box-folder 106/6)
      - Suite for Mario (piano), Photocopied manuscript score (Box-folder 106/7)
    - Tansman, Alexandre
      - Sonata no. 4 (piano), Printed score (Box-folder 106/8)
    - Toch, Ernst
      - Konzert (violoncello, chamber orchestra), Printed score (Box-folder 106/9)
      - Untitled (string quartet), Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 106/10)
    - Weiner, Lazar
      - Songs (voice, piano), Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 106/11)
    - Zea, David
      - Dark night (piano), Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 106/12)
      - Preface (chorus), Photocopied holograph manuscript vocal rehearsal score (Box-folder 106/13)
    - Unidentifed
      - Il povero diavolo (voices, piano), Photocopied printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 106/14)
- Libretti, 1920-1965 (Box 107-108)
  - Works with opus number, 1920-1965
    - Op. 20: La mandragola, see also ML96.C34 no. 99 (Box-folder 107/1)
    - Op. 94: I giganti della Montagna (Box-folder 107/2)
    - Op. 98: Aucassin et Nicolette (Box-folder 107/3-4)
    - Op. 122: Sacred service for Sabbath eve (Box-folder 107/5)
    - Op. 140: The book of Ruth (Box-folder 107/6-7)
    - Op. 141: Evangelion (Box-folder 107/8)
    - Op. 182: All's well that ends well (Box-folder 107/9-21)
    - Op. 191: Saul (Box-folder 108/1-2)
    - Op. 198: The importance of being ernest (Box-folder 108/3-4)
    - Op. 200: The book of Esther (Box-folder 108/5)
  - Other works, 1954, undated
    - Jephtha and his daughter: a dramatic cantata (Box-folder 108/6)
    - Miscellaneous excerpts, Includes: The odyssey (Homer); Ocho comedias y ocho entremeses, El rufián viudo, The interludes of Cervantes, Trampagos, and The widower bully (Cervantes) (Box-folder 108/7-8)
    - Ode to Zion (Box-folder 108/9)
    - Reconstruction symphony (Box-folder 108/10)
    - Return to Zion (Box-folder 108/11)
    - The song of Deborah (Box-folder 108/12)
    - The tempest (Box-folder 108/13)
    - Three psalms by Josephus (Box-folder 108/14)
    - Tobias and the angel (Box-folder 108/15-16)
    - The Trojan women (Box-folder 108/17)
    - The Winter's tale (Box-folder 108/18-19)
- Writings, 1919-1997 (Box 109-119)
  - Works by Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco, 1919-1967
    - Books
      - Una vita di musica, 1967, Manuscript and typescript drafts, correspondence, partial English translations, and appendices (Box 109-113)
      - La penna perduta, 1939, Typescript drafts; Compilation of published articles by Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco, prepared as a book (Box-folder 114/1-2)
      - Under the sign of Orpheus, 1959, Manuscript and typescript drafts, correspondence, clippings, and other materials; Lecture series, prepared as a book (Box-folder 114/4-17)
    - Articles
      - Alfredo Casella. La rassegna musicale, vol. 27, no. 3, (September 1957), pp. 201-204, Photocopied article (Box-folder 115/1)
      - Alfredo Casella e il suo "terzo stile". Il pianoforte, vol. 6, no. 8-9, (August-September 1925), pp. 241-247, Photocopied article (Box-folder 115/2)
      - Colloqui con Toscanini. Maggio musicale fiorentino, vol. 30, (1967), pp. 3-6, Printed article (Box-folder 115/3)
      - From a lifetime in music: Puccini, Schoenberg, Stravinsky, and others. Grand Street, vol. 9, no. 1, (Autumn 1989), pp. 150-165, Printed article (Box-folder 115/4)
      - Gianandrea Gavazzeni e "La casa di Arlecchino", 1957, Manuscript and typescript (Box-folder 115/5)
      - The guitar, that beautiful and mysterious instrument... ., 1958 June, Manuscript and typescript; Liner notes for Segovia: Golden Jubilee. Decca, 1958 (Box-folder 115/6)
      - Ildebrando Pizzetti e la sua musica corale. Il pianoforte, vol. 2, no. 8, (August 1921), pp. 233-240, Photocopied article (Box-folder 115/7)
      - Incontri letterari. Letteratura, vol. 3, no. 3-4, (January-April 1955), pp. 53-65, Photocopied article (Box-folder 115/8)
      - Jewish background of an exiled musician. The American Jewish Outlook, (July 26, 1940), Printed and photocopied articles; Also published as: My musical background. The Southern Israelite, (1940), and as Modern composer tells story of life. The Jewish Press, (June 21, 1940) (Box-folder 115/9)
      - Kurvenaldo, 1957, Manuscript and typescript; Published in Testimonianze per Loria. Letteratura, no. 30, (1957), pp. 22-30 (Box-folder 115/10)
      - Leggendo "Les noces" di Strawinski. Il pianoforte, vol. 8, no. 1, (January 1927), pp. 15-25, Photocopied article (Box-folder 115/11)
      - Lettera da firenze. Il pianoforte, 1921-1929, 13 photocopied articles (Box-folder 115/12)
      - Mendelssohn, 1964?, Manuscript and typescript; Published in Enciclopedia de la musica, 1964 (Box-folder 115/13)
      - Il mercante di Venezia. Maggio musicale viorentino, vol. 24, (1961), pp. 23-26, Printed article (Box-folder 115/14)
      - Modern Italian music. Boston Evening Transcript, (December 16, 1939), Manuscript, typescript, and printed article; Title on manuscript: About modern Italian music and about myself (Box-folder 115/15)
      - Mozart a firenze, 1935, Typescript; Published in Illustrazione toscana e dell’Etruria, 2nd ser., vol. 13, (1935), pp. 37–40 (Box-folder 115/16)
      - Music and movies, 1940 February 29, Manuscript and typescript (Box-folder 115/17)
      - Problems in writing songs, 1939 November 19-20, Manuscript and typescript; Published as: Music and poetry: problems of a writer of songs. Musical Quarterly, v. 30, no. 1 (January 1944), pp. 102-111 (Box-folder 115/18)
      - Music for the synagogue. Journal of Synagogue Music, vol. 5, no. 3, (December 1974), pp. 9-15, Printed article (Box-folder 115/19)
      - Music of the times: a composer on writing concertos. New York Times, (October 29, 1939), Manuscript, typescript, and printed article (Box-folder 115/20)
      - My experiences in Jewish music. Jewish Music Notes, (May 1951), pp. 3-4, Manuscript, typescript, and printed articles; Revised version published in Jewish Music Notes, (October 1951), p. 3 (Box-folder 115/21)
      - The overture-form in the music of today. Musical America, (February 10, 1940), pp. 108-110, Manuscript, typescript, and printed article; Title on manuscript: About writing overtures (Box-folder 115/22)
      - La "Pisanella" di I. Pizzetti. La critica musicale, vol. 2, no. 9-10, (September-October 1919), pp. 157-169, Photocopied article (Box-folder 115/23)
      - Pizzetti visto da lontano, 1956 March 19, Manuscript; Laid in: Typescript letters to Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco, 1955-1956; Published in La citta dannunziana a Ildebrando Pizzetti, ed. M. la Morgia, 1958 (Box-folder 115/24)
      - Schubert, undated, Manuscript and typescript; Published in Encyclopedia musicale (Box-folder 115/25)
      - Schubertiade, circa 1932?, Manuscript (Box-folder 115/26)
      - Schumann, 1964, Manuscript and typescript; Published in Enciclopedia de la musica, 1964 (Box-folder 115/27)
      - Shakspere [sic] and music. Shakespeare Association Bulletin, vol. 15, no. 3, (July 1940), pp. 166-174, Manuscript and printed article (Box-folder 115/28)
      - To the music editor: the Italian overture. New York Times, (April 14, 1940), Typescript and printed article (Box-folder 115/29)
      - Una lettera dall' Americirca Firenze a Ildebrando Pizzetti, (March 1947), Photocopied article (Box-folder 115/30)
    - Program notes
      - Op. 94: I giganti della montagna, Manuscript and typescript; Undated (Box-folder 116/1)
      - Op. 98: Aucassin et Nicolette, Manuscript, typescript, and printed notes; Undated; Published as "The American premiere of Aucassin and Nicolette." The Composer and Conductor, vol. 6, no. 3 (February 1964), p. 1 (Box-folder 116/2)
      - Op. 115: The birthday of the infanta, Manuscript; Undated (Box-folder 116/3)
      - Op. 151: The book of Jonah, Manuscript; Undated (Box-folder 116/4)
      - Op. 164: Overture to Much ado about nothing, Manuscript and typescript, with photocopied musical examples; Undated (Box-folder 116/5)
      - Op. 172: The song of songs, Manuscript and typescript; On p. 5 of typescript: 18 Giugno, 1955 (Box-folder 116/6)
      - Op. 181: The merchant of Venice, Manuscript and typescript; Undated; Published as "Confessioni di un autore: Il mercante di Venezia." Maggio musicale (Box-folder 116/7)
      - Op. 188: Il bestiario, Manuscript and typescript; Undated (Box-folder 116/8)
      - Recordings of Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco for RCA Victor, Typescript; Undated (Box-folder 116/9)
    - Miscellany
      - Catalogo delle compositioni, 1933 November 26, Bound photocopies of manuscripts; 3 vols. (Box-folder 116/10)
      - Ideas about musical criticism, undated, Typescript (Box-folder 116/11)
      - Interviews with Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco, 1928, 1939, Typescript and printed articles (Box-folder 116/12)
      - The Jewish chapter of my autobiography, 1940, Manuscript and typescript (Box-folder 116/13)
      - Lists of works and performances, undated, Manuscript and typescript (Box-folder 116/14)
      - Melodia (e thema), undated, Manuscript and typescript (Box-folder 116/15)
      - Music and poetry: problems of an opera composer, 1952, Manuscript; Lecture for the American Musicological Society (Box-folder 116/16)
      - Music under Italian fascism, 1944, Manuscript; Lecture for the Musicians Congress (Box-folder 116/17)
      - Notes on composers, undated, Manuscript (Box-folder 116/18)
      - Office of War Information broadcast, 1944, Manuscript (Box-folder 116/19)
      - Perfezione di Mozart, undated, Manuscript and typescript (Box-folder 116/20)
      - Postscriptum [for his article on Pizzetti], 1960 August 21, Manuscript and typescript (Box-folder 116/21)
      - Reminiscences of Italian festivals, undated, Manuscript and typescript (Box-folder 116/22)
  - Works about Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco by others, 1925-1997
    - Books
      - Rossi, Nick. Catalogue of works by Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco. New York: The International Castelnuovo-Tedesco Society, 1997, Annotated; Laid in: Rossi, Nick. "The evolution of the complete catalogue" (Box-folder 117/1)
      - La sua fede. UCLA, 1982, 2 copies; Clara Castelnuovo-Tedesco interviewed by R. Andrade; On title page: completed under the auspices of the Oral History Program (Box-folder 117/2-3)
      - Taylor, Robert. Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco: complete bibliography (up to 1962), [1962], Annotated typescript drafts and bound volumes; On cover of final revision: June 17, 1966 (Box-folder 117/4-9)
      - Westby, James. Castelnuovo-Tedesco in America: The film music. UCLA, 1994, Typescript draft, photocopied musical examples, and filmography (Box-folder 118/1-6)
    - Articles
      - Burns, Jeffrey. Le opere di Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco, trans. Maria L. Lazzarini. [unidentified publication], pp. 68-69 (Box-folder 119/1)